<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A most excellent eloquent speech made, not by an irreligious, rebellious, improbous, impious, sedicious, pestiferous, pernicious, factious, flagitious, vicious, vafritious, mischievous, malicious, mutinous, luxurious, letcherous, &amp;c. noble peer, but by a most noble and wise pious and vertuous emperor, viz., Alexander Severus to the common people of Rome, assembled before him in Pompey's Theatre : with the causes, as likewise the effects thereof, which were an humble and real cordial verbal address, to his imperial majesty, of all their lives and fortunes : being a rare pattern of pagan piety and obedience : with a few quintessential queries and remarques thereupon : calculated for the meridian of the famous city of London, buy may prove of singualr service and infallible use to all the atheistical, dissenting, disloyal, and phanatical subjects of His Sacred Majesty of Great-Brittain, France, and Ireland, &amp;c. without the least preceptible error or mistake in the world / made English out of Greek.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1683</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 34 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 11 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A59396</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S2818</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R2688</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11781979</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11781979</idno>
            <idno type="VID">49123</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A59396)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 49123)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 547:18)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A most excellent eloquent speech made, not by an irreligious, rebellious, improbous, impious, sedicious, pestiferous, pernicious, factious, flagitious, vicious, vafritious, mischievous, malicious, mutinous, luxurious, letcherous, &amp;c. noble peer, but by a most noble and wise pious and vertuous emperor, viz., Alexander Severus to the common people of Rome, assembled before him in Pompey's Theatre : with the causes, as likewise the effects thereof, which were an humble and real cordial verbal address, to his imperial majesty, of all their lives and fortunes : being a rare pattern of pagan piety and obedience : with a few quintessential queries and remarques thereupon : calculated for the meridian of the famous city of London, buy may prove of singualr service and infallible use to all the atheistical, dissenting, disloyal, and phanatical subjects of His Sacred Majesty of Great-Brittain, France, and Ireland, &amp;c. without the least preceptible error or mistake in the world / made English out of Greek.</title>
                  <author>Severus Alexander, Emperor of Rome, 208-235.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 18 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for W. Davis ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London?] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1683.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Citizenship --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-07</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:49123:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A MOST EXCELLENT Eloquent Speech, MADE, NOT BY An <hi>Irreligious, Rebellious, Improbous, Impious, Seditious, Peſtiferous, Pernicious, Factious, Flagitious, Vicious, Vafritious, Miſchievous, Malicious, Mutinous, Luxurious, Letcherous,</hi> &amp;c. NOBLE PEER; <hi>B<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>T BY</hi> A moſt Noble and Wiſe, Pious and Vertuous EMPEROR, <hi>(VIZ.)</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Alexander Severus,</hi> To the <hi>Common People</hi> of <hi>ROME,</hi> Aſſembled before him in <hi>POMPEY</hi>'S THEATRE.</p>
            <p>With the CAUSES, as likewiſe the EFFECTS thereof, which were an Humble and Real Cordial Verbal <hi>ADDRESS,</hi> to His Imperial Majeſty, of all their <hi>Lives</hi> and <hi>Fortunes;</hi> Being a Rare Pattern of <hi>Pagan</hi> Piety and <hi>Obedience.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Made Engliſh out of the Greek.</p>
            <p>With a few <hi>Quinteſsential Queries</hi> and <hi>Remarques</hi> thereupon. Calculated for the Meridian of the Famous City of <hi>LONDON,</hi> but may prove of ſingular Service and Infallible Uſe to all the <hi>Atheiſtical, Diſſenting, Diſloyal,</hi> and <hi>Phanatical</hi> Subjects of His Sacred Majeſty of <hi>Great-Brittain, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> &amp;c. without the leaſt Preceptible Error or Miſtake in the World.</p>
            <q xml:lang="lat">
               <l>Diviſum Imperium cum Jove <hi>Ceſar</hi> habet.</l>
               <bibl>Virgil.</bibl>
            </q>
            <q xml:lang="lat">
               <p>Principilus ſummum rerum Arbitrium Dij dederunt; ſubditis obſequij Gloria vero relicta eſt.</p>
               <bibl>Tacit. 4. Annal.</bibl>
            </q>
            <p>Printed for <hi>W. Davis,</hi> in <hi>Amen-Corner.</hi> M.DC.LXXXIII.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:49123:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:49123:2"/>
            <head>
               <hi>A moſt</hi> Excellent <hi>and</hi> Eloquent ORATION, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>BEfore I come to this Incomparable Speech it ſelf, you are to be acquainted with ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing concerning the Cauſe thereof, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to promiſe, which in ſhort was this follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing.</p>
            <p>This good Emperor one day looking out at his Palace Window,<note place="margin">The cauſe of this Speech.</note> chanc'd to ſee certain <hi>Gentlemen</hi> Exerciſing themſelves in Wreſtling, Running, Leaping, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> To whom there happen'd to come a certain number of <hi>Common People;</hi> who, without any ſign of Reverence or Reſpect, or ſo much as ſaying by your leave, intruded themſelves into the <hi>Gentlemens</hi> Society; and Malapertly undertook with arrogant and preſumptious ſawcy Language, to contend with them about thoſe their Recreati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons; Now the <hi>Gentlemen</hi> being therewith offend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, bad them be content with their own Degree and Stations, and go and aſſociate themſelves with their Companions and Equals. But theſe <hi>Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers</hi> taking this Reproof as a grand Affront; with ſturdy ſtubborn Countenances, proudly made this Reply; <hi>viz.</hi> That every one of them was able to live, and had more ſtore and plenty wherewith
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:49123:3"/>to follow their Pleaſures than the beſt of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves. Inſomuch, as if the Emperor's Guards had not interven'd in ſeaſon, the <hi>Commons</hi> had fought with the <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> and, in all propability, had worſted them, being more by far in number than they.</p>
            <p>Now the Emperor viewing theſe paſſages, was perceiv'd to be put into ſuch a paſſion thereby, as was obſerv'd never to have been ſeen in him, during all his paſt life-time; and thereupon caus'd the ſaid <hi>Common People</hi> to be ſecur'd, every Man of them, and ſtrictly commanded, that not any thing that had paſſed ſhould be taken notice of in the leaſt, until his farther Will and Pleaſure were made known concerning the ſame: And immediately thereupon ſends for the Governour of the City and <hi>Tribunes,</hi> and commands them to ſend their Officers, to Summon <hi>all</hi> the Men <hi>Commons</hi> of <hi>Rome,</hi> to appear in <hi>Pompey</hi>'s Theatre the <hi>2d.</hi> day follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing; where the Emperor in his own Perſon would alſo be preſent, and declare unto them ſome things of very great Weight and Moment, concerning the moſt Important and Perillous Affairs of the State of the Weal-Public.</p>
            <p>The Emperor's Commands were accordingly Executed; and an High Place Erected on pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe at the end of the Theatre, where the Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peror himſelf ſhould ſit in his Majeſty, that all the people might plainly behold and perfectly hear him.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:49123:3"/>
            <p> Now the Theatre was made in form of a Bow that hath a great Bend;<note place="margin">A Deſcription of <hi>Pompey</hi>'s Theatre.</note> and in all the round part thereof, were many Benches, one behind another, and over one another, (for it was narroweſt be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, and upward grew larger and larger) and there ſat all the <hi>Common People;</hi> and at the ſtreight end, which was to the other part, as the String to the Bow, were the Seats for the Senators, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hind them ſat the <hi>Gentlemen.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>At the time appointed, the People being in the <hi>Theatre</hi> according as they were commanded, the Emperor came in Perſon, accompanied only with the Governour and <hi>Tribunes,</hi> leaving all his Guards at the <hi>Theatre</hi> Gate.</p>
            <p>At his coming all the people roſe, and Saluted him with moſt joyful Acclamations; but he, good Man, contrary to his accuſtomed Cuſtome, paſſ'd by them with a diſpleaſed Countenance: whereat they were not a little amazed, and with hearts full of dutiful, loving dread, and general conſtant Si<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence, prepar'd their Ears to hear attentively what the Emperor would ſay; who, after he had long view'd them, with a Grave Countenance and full of Majeſty, ſpake to them as hereafter followeth.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="speech">
                        <head>The Emperor <hi>Alexander Severus</hi>'s Speech to the Common People of <hi>Rome.</hi>
                        </head>
                        <p>WE wot not how to begin to ſpeak unto you, for we know not by what Name we ſhall call you; for if you were our <hi>Senators,</hi> then we would
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:49123:4"/>call you Fathers; if you were <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> then would we call you our Friends; and if you were, as you ought to be, good <hi>Commoners,</hi> then would we call you our good <hi>People</hi> of <hi>Rome,</hi> as you know we were wont to do. But ſince <hi>Election</hi> hath not made you <hi>Senators,</hi> nor <hi>Birth</hi> made you <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> nor your Merits <hi>good Commoners,</hi> we be in no ſmall doubt what we ſhall call you; For ſhould we call you <hi>Romans,</hi> we fear leaſt <hi>Romulus,</hi> from whom proceeded that Name, (if he be Deify'd, as you ſuppoſe he is) being therewith offended, ſhould be avenged as well on us as on you, for abuſing his Glorious Name on ſuch <hi>People,</hi> which go about to diſſolve this Noble Empire, deſtroy this City which he firſt founded with his moſt excellent Proweſs and Wiſdom; and what worſe is, if any thing can be worſe, utterly to Extinguſh the moſt Honourable and Glorious Fame of this City and People thereof, which hath pierc'd the Clouds, flown over the high Mountains, paſs'd the peril<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Seas and large Rivers, ran through the vaſt Deſarts and Wilderneſſes, and touch'd the farther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt Bounds of the World: We will therefore omit to call you by any Name, until we can find out a proper one, and according to your deſerts.</p>
                        <p>Perhaps at our coming, you beholding our Countenance towards you more ſtrange than it was formerly wont to be; you thought, I ſay, it may be, that we were moved by ſome private Diſpleaſure, for ſomething touching our particular Perſon; or that we were alter'd from our former Temperance to Tyranny, conceiving ſome Suſpicion of our
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:49123:4"/>Nature, by the remembrance of that Monſter in Nature, our late Predeceſſor <hi>Heliogabaius,</hi> foraſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>much as we both came from one Lineage, which I deny not: But truly if this be your phantaſie, we will ſoon acquit our ſelf thereof, and ſet all your minds at Liberty.</p>
                        <p>We will then ſay thus much to you; As touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing our Perſon and Family, no Man by Words hath offended us; no Man hath taken any thing from us; no Man, that we know, hath gone about to betray us, or conſpire againſt us: Nor is there any other thing privately acted to our Detriment, that hath diſpleaſed us: And as for our accuſtomed Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, which ſo well liked and contented you, we ſhall aſſure you we have not alter'd, neither intend we to alter them: For Tyranny, as we have ever had it in extream deteſtation; ſo do we now moſt fer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vently abominate and abhorr it. The Corrupt Nature of our Predeceſſor had never place in us. One Garden at one time brings forth deadly Poy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, and wholeſome Medicine. We ſee that one Woman, which by one Man hath many Children, of them ſome be fair and perſonable; ſome ill-fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour'd and Deform'd; ſome be Ingenious, and apt to receive good Learning; others we ſee be Fools and dull-witted; one we ſee is Courageous and Hardy, another is a Daſtard and a Coward; this Child is gentle and inclin'd to vertue, that's fierce and full of Vice. Now this is no new thing, but in daily experience: and if this diverſity and varity then happens to be in one Garden, and in the Generation of one Father, and alſo of one Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:49123:5"/>then I hope we may well eſcape the cauſe of this Suſpicion. We and <hi>Heliogabalus</hi> had ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Fathers and ſeveral Mothers, and they as diffe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent in their Conditions, as you your ſelves can bear witneſs; who have known and ſeen experi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>enced the Chaſte living, Sanctity and Prudence of our Reverend Mother; and in what vertuous Diſcipline She hath nurtur'd us, and brought us up, unto the time that we were called to this Dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity by God; and this ought certainly to ſuffice, as well to perſuade you that not any thing con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning our ſelf, hath moved us to diſpleaſure to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards you; as alſo to Exclude all ſuſpicion of Tyranny out of your minds: and now ſhall you know the real cauſe why we be at this time diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>contented with you.</p>
                        <p>Although we ſaid at the beginning that you went about to diſſolve this Empire, deſtroy this City, and extinguiſh the Glorious Fame thereof, which indeed is the cauſe of our diſpleaſure and heavineſs; yet in thoſe general Words, you per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive not I ſuppoſe, what we mean thereby: wherefore be attentive and take good heed, and you ſhall hear it more particularly declared unto you.</p>
                        <p>After <hi>Romulus</hi> had Built this City,<note place="margin">Romulus.</note> he, by his Divine Reaſon, conſidered, and, as I doubt not, in the time of the Building, Experience declared, That in a confuſed multitude of People, and they being of divers Wits and Conditions, if <hi>Order</hi> were wanting, there would be no perpetual Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cord; but the People of neceſſity, would be com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pell'd,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:49123:5"/>by continual variance and diſcord, either to abandon the City, and, dividing themſelves, to ſeek for ſundry places to inhabit in, or elſe, abiding there in continual Sedition, would ſhortly and eaſily be ſubdued or deſtroyed by their Neighbors dwelling about them: Wherefore he proceeding from a Gentile and Noble Houſe, excelling the reſidue of the people in Noble Courage and fine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of Wit, firſt deviſed and eſtabliſhed this Order; <hi>viz.</hi> That the Company which he had Aſſembled, as well of them which he had brought unto him, as of thoſe which he, out of divers parts, had allured with him, ſhould generally be called by the Name of <hi>Romans,</hi> for ever: and that of them ſhould be Three States or Degrees, every one of them neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary for the <hi>Weal-Public</hi> of his Noble City, in their ſundry Adminiſtrations, Stations, Duties, and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erciſes.</p>
                        <p>For the firſt State he choſe, out of the whole Congregation, an hundred Men, Ancient in years; which, in Moderation of Living, Soberneſs of Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, and ſharpneſs of Wit, were the principall Perſonages of all that number. Of theſe he E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtabiſhed a Council, whereby the Affairs of the City and the Appendices thereof ſhould be Ruled and Miniſtred; and theſe Counſellors, for their Age, ſhould be called <hi>Senators,</hi>
                           <note place="margin">Senators</note> (for <hi>Senes</hi> in <hi>Latine</hi> ſignifies old Men) notwithſtanding, being ſaluted or ſpoken to, they ſhould be named Fathers: as alſo the College or Company of them, was Incorporate by the Name of the <hi>Senate.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <pb n="8" facs="tcp:49123:6"/>
                        <p> Moreover, out of this College ſhould be Elected the chief Judges and Officers in the <hi>Weal-Public,</hi> to whom ſhould be committed the determination of Juſtice, the Execution of Ceremonies and So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lemn Sacrifices, and other Authorities which belong to Government: Wherefore he would that in this State there ſhould be a Majeſty, which, of all o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Men, ſhould be had in ſingular Honour and Reverence.</p>
                        <p>Now as this State was ordained for Counſel and Government; ſo likewiſe he Elected, out of the redſidue, which were Luſty in years, Valiant, Hardy, and Courageous, a greater number; whom, becauſe in Wars they ſhould be on Horſe-back, he called <hi>Equites;</hi>
                           <note place="margin">Equites. Equeſtris.</note> and the other he called <hi>Equeſtris,</hi> to them ſhould chiefly pertain the defence of the City a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Invaſion of Enemies, with other ſmall Adminiſtrations about the neceſſary Proviſions and Ornaments of this Noble City.</p>
                        <p>And this State alſo would he have Honoured of the reſt of the People; and to the intent they ſhould be known from other Men, he aſſigned them to wear a Ring, and to bear Javelins in their hands; from whence afterwards they were called <hi>Quirites,</hi>
                           <note place="margin">Quirites.</note> which in the ancient Tongue of this Country, ſignified <hi>Spear-Men.</hi> Out of this State ſhould be Elected the <hi>Senators,</hi> when the juſt num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber of the <hi>Senate</hi> decayed,</p>
                        <p>The third State was of the <hi>baſe People,</hi>
                           <note place="margin">The Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers.</note> or <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moners,</hi> to whom ſeverally ſhould not be Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mited any Authority, but ſhould imploy and buſie themſelves in their proper Occupations, and be
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:49123:6"/>ready at all times to Execute the Statutes and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinances made by the <hi>Senate;</hi>
                           <note place="margin">Note, That <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mulus</hi> was none of the three States.</note> as alſo to be obedient to the chief Officers in what pertained to the <hi>Weal-Public:</hi> And moreover when Wars requir'd, that they ſhould go forth, then were they to be o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bedient and diligent at the Commands of their Captains and Leaders.</p>
                        <p>This <hi>Order</hi> being Eſtabliſhed by <hi>Romulus,</hi> as long as, in every degree, it was duely obſerved, how marvelouſly did this City proſper? yea, how won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derfully did a few <hi>Romans,</hi> in reſpect, not only de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend this little Territory, againſt the great number and vaſt Puiſſance of divers and ſundry people, confederated againſt them, but alſo beat them back to their own houſes; entred into their Cities, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpoil'd them of their ſubſtance, and alſo compell'd them, not only to deſire perpetual Peace, but more<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>over, at the laſt, to become their Subjects and Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>butaries? And when this good <hi>Order</hi> began to be broken, your <hi>Common State</hi> aſpiring to Government and Rule, where they were ordain'd to obey only; What Year, I pray, can ye find free from Sedition and Diſcord among you? Who can number the <hi>Romans</hi> which have been ſlain in Civil Wars and <hi>Commotions?</hi> Who could, without tears,<note place="margin">The Ld. <hi>Ruſſel</hi> would call theſe but Stirrs.</note> write the dolorous State of this City in the time of <hi>Cinna</hi> and <hi>Marius,</hi> whom, for diſdain that they had for the Nobility, you Elevated to the higheſt Digni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties? By this your Diſorder, ſundry Calamities befell this City: you choſe <hi>Caligula</hi> to be your Emperor, and where could there be found a more horrible Tyrant? in the which Name he ſo much
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:49123:7"/>delighted, that often, looking in a Glaſs, he would moſt exactly form his Viſage to the moſt terrible faſhion: Alſo in recompence of your kindneſs, he wiſh'd that all the people of <hi>Rome</hi> had but one Neck, that he might ſtrike it off at one ſtroke.</p>
                        <p>I'm aſham'd to reherſe my Predeceſſor and Kinſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man <hi>Heliogabalus,</hi> that deteſtable Veſſel of Abo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mination: but <hi>you</hi> ought rather to be aſham'd that vou, ſetting apart ſo great a number of Honourable Perſonages, as were then in the <hi>Senate,</hi> for their Experience, Wiſdom, and Proweſs, worthy every one of them to be Emperors, choſe the ſaid <hi>Helioga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>balus,</hi> a Stranger born, a Boy in Years, a Fool, in reſpect of their Wiſdom, to be your Soveraign Lord; who brought you to the moſt vile Subjecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on that any people were in the World? For is there any thing in Mankind ſo vile, as to be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Condition of brute Beaſts? What Beaſt can you name, that will ſuffer, in his preſence, an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other Beaſt to Occupy, in the act of Generation, her whom he hath choſen for his Mate and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panion; but to his power will reſiſt and fight with him? <hi>Heliogabalus</hi> held you in ſuch Slavery, that, partly to avoid his diſpleaſure, partly to Flatter him, and get ſomewhat of him, you not only ſuffer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him to abuſe your Wives and your Children, ſuch as beſt liked him; but alſo increas'd your Brothel-Houſes, and with open eyes let your Wives and your Children daily and nighly haunt 'em; and openly in the Streets, which I abhorr to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herſe, pick up Men and provoke them to Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chery.</p>
                        <pb n="11" facs="tcp:49123:7"/>
                        <p> I omit, for ſhortneſs of time, many ſuch other Elections, which have proceeded from your groſs and preſumptuous Wits, after you had tranſgreſſed the <hi>Order,</hi> wherein <hi>Romulus</hi> left you, and exceeded the bounds of your Office and Dutys; which at laſt was perceiv'd by you, as I ſuppos'd, when you, being tedious of that Beaſtly Liberty and Licenſe, which that Beaſt <hi>Heliogabalus</hi> gave freely to you, had ſlain him, and took me to be your Emperor; although with all my power I refus'd that burthen, until I was, by the <hi>Senate</hi> and you, conſtrain'd to take it upon me; and then did you deſire me to reduce the State of this City to its firſt <hi>Order.</hi> About which I have laboured theſe 8 years, with not a little pains, ſtudy, and labour; beginning at mine own Houſhould; to the intent, that as well by the example of my Servants and Officers, you and others being under my Rule, might the ſooner reform your ſelves; as alſo that you might the bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter perceive and be leſs offended with my Severity.</p>
                        <p>And becauſe I ſaw much ill Example proceed from the <hi>Senate;</hi> and alſo that you were oppreſſed with the Pride and Corruption of Judges and Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, I, uſing much diligence, weeded them out, and diſcharged them of their Authorities; nay, they went not unpuniſhed according to their de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerts.</p>
                        <p>I purged alſo the State of <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> from <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>balds</hi> and <hi>Riotors,</hi> and advancing others thereunto, I caus'd them to be daily exerciſed in Acts of Proweſs; or elſe to hear Leſſons in ſuch matters of Doctrine, as thereby they might acquire more
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:49123:8"/>Wiſdom, to be Officers or Counſellors in the <hi>Weal-Public:</hi> only the State of the <hi>Common People</hi> I did not viſit, ſaving in puniſhing of Theeves; foraſmuch as I judg'd, that they had leaſt Liberty to do any great evil, being, as I ſaid, oppreſs'd with Tyran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny. And that thoſe Vices which were among them, like as they were taken by the Example of their Superiors; ſo I truſted that by their Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment the ſaid ill manners would be forſaken: and by the virtuous Example of ſuch honeſt Men, as I have put in their places, good Manners ſhould be as gladly embraced.</p>
                        <p>But now I perceive all hath hap'ned contrary to my expectation; for the ſparing of you and the correcting my own Servants, with the ſharp Refor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of the <hi>Senate</hi> and <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> hath brought you to ſuch a heigth of <hi>Preſumption</hi> and <hi>Arrogancy,</hi> that you contend and ſtrive to be equal with the <hi>Gentry,</hi> uſing no form of Reverence unto them; either becauſe you think and imagine that I fear your Puiſſance more than I favour their Honeſties; or elſe that your Riches make you ſo proud; which you abuſing in exceſſive Uſuries, have there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with devour'd the Patrimonies of many young <hi>Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen,</hi> and have made them Beggars: or, by the ſeverity of the ancient Laws of this City, taken them in Bondage and ſlain them in Irons. And by ſuch colorable Rapine, you have bought great <hi>Poſſeſſions</hi> in <hi>Greece, Sicily, Spain,</hi> &amp;c. whereby you accumu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>late Treaſures and Pleaſures like to great Princes.</p>
                        <p>If you think me to be afraid of your Puiſſance, your opinion is falſe; for, above all things, I moſt
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:49123:8"/>deſire to dye for the defence of the <hi>Weal-Public</hi> of this Noble City: And indeed, rather will I dye than ſee the Calamities which needs muſt enſue thereupon, if <hi>Order</hi> be not kept, as I have before declar'd.</p>
                        <p>At that word all the <hi>People</hi> cry'd out with one <hi>voice,</hi> pouring out tears from their eyes; <hi>Live moſt No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble and Gracious Emperor, he that would your death, let him dye, let him be rent into pieces; our Puiſſance ſhall never annoy you, but, unto death, ſhall defend you; you have reſtored us unto life that were dead<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> unto Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty that were in Captivity; unto Honour that were diſhonoured. Live long vertuous Emperor, and what you find amiſs and faulty in us, reform it, and we ſhall obey you; and he that ſhall offer to reſiſt and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bell, let him be ſlain, and drawn with an Hook through the City, and thrown into</hi> Tiber. <hi>You are, in Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, our Father, whom we chiefly will Honour; in Age you be our moſt dear Son, whom we will fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour more than our own Lives; and they often cry'd out, Live moſt gentle and Righteous Emperor.</hi>
                        </p>
                        <p>Hereat the Emperor relented, and with much ado kept the tears from flowing from his eyes; and after he had ſetled his Spirits and Countenance, he then ſpeak to them farther, after this manner; I am glad that you have declared, that there is yet in you ſome portion of Loyalty; which gives me hope that neither the Noble Renown of this City, began by <hi>Romulus,</hi> and augmented by other Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Governors; nor my labours in reſtoring thereof, when it was decay'd, and likely to periſh, ſhall prove of none effect: But if you be conſtant,
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:49123:9"/>in this Affection, I truſt that very ſhortly the <hi>Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lic-Weal</hi> ſhall flouriſh, and that this City and Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple ſhall be in as much eſtimation, as ever it was in the time of any of our Progenitors.</p>
                        <p>And now have I found again your old Name whereby I will call you; the Children and Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors of the vertuous <hi>Romans,</hi> I ſay, you moſt Victorious People, Branches of <hi>Romulus,</hi> Subduers of Realms; Samplers of Vertue, and Proweſs to all the world; mitigate your covetous Appetites, expell from you Avarice, vale your high Courages; I mean in exceeding the bounds of your Popular State; and comparing your ſelves with your Supe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riors; be Charitable and Merciful to your own Country-Men, where their neceſſity may be reliev'd with your plenty: Be aſhamed that People of o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Countries, People rude and barbarous, ſhould condemn you of Cruelty for deſtroying your <hi>Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try;</hi> the chief Ornament and Defence of this Noble City: That they ſhould reproach you of Rudeneſs and Pride, in omitting to do Reverence to them that do in Order excell you. Remember, that as if the State of the <hi>Senators</hi> decays, ſuch of the <hi>Gentry</hi> are Elected into the <hi>Senate,</hi> as are vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuous; ſo you that ſhall be found equal to them in virtue (for your Subſtance and Riches only can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not make you <hi>Gentlemen</hi>) ſhall be advanced to the State of <hi>Gentlemen,</hi> according to Reaſon: And then conſider with your ſelves, if you would not then your ſelves require to be preferr'd in Reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rence? For nothing certainly ſhall cauſe a Man more willingly to do his duty, than to think what
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:49123:9"/>would require of him that is inferior to him: and it hath been ſaid of Wiſe Men; That he that would be a Ruler, ſhould firſt learn to be a good Subject: for truly a proud and covetous Subject, will never make a mild and temperate Governor.</p>
                        <p>And now have I no more to ſay unto you; but that you apply your ſelves with all your hearts, to reſtore this City to its former Ancient and Laudable <hi>Order;</hi> as I ſhall endeavour my ſelf by Example and diligence, to bring e're long to its perfect Perfection.</p>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The Effects of the foregoing SPEECH.</head>
               <p>THus ended this moſt Noble and Wiſe Emperor's Oration; and ſo he departed, the Effect where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of was, beſides what you have heard already, that all the <hi>Common People</hi> followed him home with theſe loud Acclamations; <hi>The Gods Immortal pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve and defend you, moſt Noble Emperor; you are the Crown of our Glory, of our Wealth and Proſperity; hated be he of the Gods and of Men, that would you diſpleaſure; do you with us what beſt liketh you, and ſo the Immortal Gods defend you.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And now Reader, having lay'd before thee an al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt incomparable pattern of Common <hi>Pagan</hi> Loy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty and Obedience of Subjects to their Superiors, I wiſh it may have the ſame <hi>Effect</hi> on them for whom it was now publiſhd, as it had on them for whom it was firſt made. And I would only be reſolv'd in a few very Important <hi>Queries,</hi> by our unnatural ungrate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful diſloyal, and hypocritical Prig-Prince <hi>Presbyters</hi> of theſe times, and all other their Seditious, Factious, Rebellious, <hi>Fratres in malo,</hi> Brethren in Iniquity,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:49123:10"/>but chiefly of <hi>Jack Presbyter,</hi> becauſe I look upon him, in my weak opinion, always to have been, and at preſent are, and ever will be, if not prevented, the moſt dangerous and formidable Enemy to Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narchy and Hiearchy of any within His Sacred Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Dominions; and ſo I ſhall conclude.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>1ſt.</hi> then let me ask you whether you don't imagine that theſe Dutiful &amp; Loyal <hi>Pagans</hi> ſhall one day riſe in Judgement againſt you for your damnable Diſloy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alty and Rebellion, againſt two ſo good, ſo gracious, ſo mild, ſo merciful mirrors of Majeſty, Father and Son, and to be acknowledged, by all true Subjects, <hi>Gods Anointed</hi> and our Terreſtial God?<note n="*" place="margin">And whether it ſhall not be more tollerable for <hi>Tyre</hi> and <hi>Sydon,</hi> &amp;c. in that Day than for you</note> And whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther it do not exactly reſemble the <hi>Lucifero-machy</hi> and <hi>Giganto-machy</hi> of Old? which if they would but conſider, may one day prove ſomewhat available to them, towards their Eternal Happineſs and timely Repentance, and preventing their future Eternal Damnation.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Secondly,</hi> What Account they will, one day, be able to give Almighty God, for not only, as this good Emperor complain'd of in his Common Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, their Cruelty and Barbariety in deſtroying their Gentry, the chief Ornament and Defence of their City, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And that Rude and Barbarous peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple ſhould reproach them of their Rudeneſs and Pride, in omitting only to do Reverence to the Gentry their Superiors; <hi>&amp;c.</hi> I ſay, what Account will they be able to render at the laſt dreadful day, for their not only contemning and deſtroying their Nobles and Gentry, but the very Fountain of No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility and Gentry, <hi>viz.</hi> King <hi>Charles</hi> the I. and
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:49123:10"/>Subverting all <hi>Order,</hi> and endeavouring to make his Son, like his Father, <hi>viz.</hi> a <hi>Glorious King.</hi> For in that Curſed Tryal of King <hi>Charles</hi> the I. you'l plainly ſee the <hi>Common People</hi> Condemn'd and Murther'd their King; for there you have <hi>1ſt.</hi> An Act of the <hi>Commons,</hi> &amp;c. for Erecting an <hi>High Court of Juſtice;</hi> &amp;c. Then the <hi>Commons</hi> of <hi>England</hi> Aſſembled in <hi>Parliament,</hi> according to the Power and Fun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>damental Truſt repos'd in them by the <hi>People,</hi> &amp;c. in be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half of the <hi>Commons</hi> of <hi>England</hi> and all the <hi>People,</hi> &amp;c. in the Name of the <hi>Commons,</hi> &amp;c. the Rights and Liberties of the <hi>People,</hi> &amp;c. and on the <hi>People</hi> behalf, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> He Levyed War againſt <hi>Parliament</hi> and <hi>People</hi> therein repreſented, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> caus'd Thouſands of the <hi>Free</hi> and <hi>Good People</hi> to be ſlain; <hi>&amp;c.</hi> much Innocent Blood of the <hi>Free People</hi> ſpilt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> againſt Publick Intereſt of the <hi>People,</hi> &amp;c. And again on behalf of the <hi>People</hi> and <hi>Commons</hi> thrice, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> then, this Authority re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quires you in the Name of the <hi>People,</hi> &amp;c. in behalf of the <hi>Commons,</hi> &amp;c. in the Name of the <hi>People,</hi> &amp;c. in behalf of the <hi>People,</hi> &amp;c. by Authority of the <hi>Commons,</hi> &amp;c. Sir, the <hi>VOTE</hi> of the <hi>Commons</hi> in <hi>Parliament,</hi> is <hi>the Reaſon of the Kingdom.</hi> By Authority of the <hi>Commons:</hi> on behalf of the <hi>Commons;</hi> We ſhew you there the <hi>Commons</hi> make War a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the <hi>Parliament</hi> and <hi>People;</hi> &amp; in deſiance of the <hi>Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament,</hi> and in behalf of the <hi>People;</hi> and the Houſe of <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons</hi> the <hi>Supreme Authority of the Kingdom;</hi> and in the <hi>Peoples</hi> behalf, and in behalf of the <hi>Commons,</hi> and in the Name of the <hi>People;</hi> and the Powers and <hi>Supreme Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty</hi> of the <hi>Commons;</hi> And laſtly, in that Satanical Sentence of Death you have the <hi>Commons,</hi> &amp;c. where you may find the Words <hi>Commons, People, Parliament,</hi> nam'd <hi>Alternatim,</hi> and <hi>Vice Verſa</hi> about ſome 37, or 38 ſeveral times; but from ſuch <hi>Parliaments, People,</hi> and <hi>Commons; Good Lord de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver</hi> good King <hi>Charles</hi> and his <hi>Loyal Subjects:</hi> So that you may ſee this damn'd Idol and Oracle of the Rebells, <hi>Vox Populi,</hi> is often, if not always, <hi>Vox Diaboli:</hi> For was't not <hi>Vox Populi</hi> cry'd up <hi>Rebellious Abſalom</hi> againſt his King and <hi>Father?</hi> Was't not <hi>Vox Populi</hi> cry'd <hi>Crucifie,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:49123:11"/>
               <p> Then let me ask the <hi>People</hi> whether our preſent Dread Soveraign, hath not, under God, reſtor'd them to life that were dead; and to Liberty that were in Captivity, and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the greateſt Tyranny, as this good Emperor did his? And whether they have not as great Reaſon to <hi>Eccho</hi> as they did, <hi>Live long,</hi> &amp;c. and Addreſs their Lives and For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tunes to his diſpoſing: Whoſe Father <hi>indeed</hi> dyed in de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of the <hi>Liberties</hi> and <hi>Properties</hi> of an ungrateful Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration of Viperous <hi>Commons,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">The Ld. <hi>Ruſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel</hi>'s Word.</note> and he, now living, whom the King of Kings long hath hitherto defended, and continue among us, <hi>&amp;c. Sero abat in Coelum;</hi> would not infallibly no leſs ſuffer himſelf to become a Victime for the Rights of his <hi>Liege-People,</hi> &amp;c. as this good Emperor ſaid he was ready to do: And God grant he may <hi>Principiis obſtare</hi> as to all his Diſ-affected and Rebellious Subjects; as this Noble Emperor did; <hi>Amen, Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>As for what's ſaid about the Citizens, there's an Old Verſe for them.
<q xml:lang="lat">
                     <l>O<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Cives, Cives, querenda Pecunia primum,</l>
                     <l>Virtus poſt Nummos, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                     </l>
                  </q>
                  <q xml:lang="lat">Caveat Emptor.</q>
               </p>
               <p>Then laſtly, ſince mention is made of Tribunes, note they were thoſe Magiſtrates that were choſe to Preſerve the Rights, and aſcertain the <hi>Liberties</hi> of the <hi>Common People,</hi> againſt the Puiſſance of the Nobles: they were Inſtituted ſoon after that Notable Diſcord between the <hi>People</hi> and <hi>Nobles,</hi> which was appeaſed by <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>enenius Agrippa,</hi> who wiſelly United the <hi>Commons</hi> ſeperating themſelves from the <hi>Nobles</hi> that commanded them, and retiring to the Mount <hi>Aventine,</hi> complaining of exceſſive Impoſts laid upon them, by moralizing this following Table. The Members of the Body, ſays he, would one day ſeperate themſelves from the Belly, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny'd it their Aſſiſtance, under pretext that they were in continual labor to furniſh it with Proviſions for its Gluttony, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> This <hi>Diſcord</hi> laſted till the death of the whole Body enſued: Even ſo ſhall it happen to you the <hi>Commons,</hi> ſays he, if you ſeperate your ſelves from your <hi>Nobles;</hi> for there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by you will ruin the whole <hi>Body Politic;</hi> for though it ſeem to you that your Nobles live in Delights, Gluttoning themſelves with the beſt of your <hi>Goods,</hi> &amp;c. Yet muſt they Communicate thereof to you in a ſhort time, and ſo couſerve you; As the Belly diſtributes to the other Members, of the ſubſtance it formerly received from them, and ſo maintains the Body in perfect Health. Theſe <hi>Tribunes</hi> at laſt with the <hi>People</hi> became Inſolent; and commited many Diſorders, to the prejudice of the <hi>Nobles,</hi> &amp;c. So that they were ſometimes call'd the Peſt of the <hi>Weal-Public.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="license">
            <p>Licenſed and Entred according to Order.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
